<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
	<title>Haci&#39;s Debugging Adventures</title>
	<link>http://www.hacimuro.com/tags/fl/</link>
	<description>Recent content in FL on Haci&#39;s Debugging Adventures</description>
	<generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
	<language>en-gb</language>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 14 Sep 2023 16:40:39 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
        <atom:link href="http://www.hacimuro.com/tags/fl/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	
	
	<item>
		<title>HackAThoning</title>
		<link>http://www.hacimuro.com/blog/hackathoning/</link>
		<pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2024 20:32:02 +0000</pubDate>
		
		<guid>http://www.hacimuro.com/blog/hackathoning/</guid>
		<description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;hackathons&#34;&gt;Hackathons&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Coming from a cyber security background I always found the name hackathons strange, cyber folks are have our group all nighters and we call them CTFs (Capture the flags). It makes more sense to call CTFs hackathons in my opinion but I digress. Whilst the culture of hackathons are not healthy, with free energy drinks, snacks and ridiculous staying all night culture. It is still great fun and enables individuals to learn a lot in a short amount of time (if done correctly). I&amp;rsquo;ve been to really bad hackathons and some amazing ones, but a great hackathon ensures there is proper food, support for individuals and a 🚬 area .&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;eth-oxford&#34;&gt;Eth Oxford&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The fortnight begins at &lt;a href=&#34;https://ethoxford.io/&#34;&gt;EthOxford&lt;/a&gt; I am currently working at a startup where we&amp;rsquo;re building data analytics tools to web3 companies to provide data driven solutions. The larger goal is to provide full autonomy to DAOs. Check us out on &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Lumous-Labs&#34;&gt;github&lt;/a&gt;. So far we&amp;rsquo;ve built a data analytics to visualise community behaviours within discord servers, we are able to provide data driven insights into community to be able to identify &amp;ldquo;influencers&amp;rdquo;. Our aim at this hackathon is to provide integration with github so we can provide the same features via aggregating discord and github data, this will enable us to identify &amp;ldquo;builders&amp;rdquo; a developer with strong social presence. Working with github&amp;rsquo;s API was luckily not problematic however we were confronted with a major problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;data-pairing&#34;&gt;Data pairing&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A contingency associated with doing the builder analysis is to have pairing of discord accounts and github accounts. By pairing we can confidently state that these 2 accounts have the same owner. This was proven to be a challenge, since if this information was stored somewhere it will be in a highly unstructured area of the internet. From our analysis on the HomeDao Server we quickly realised that it was a rarity for people to link the github to their discord account. As you can see below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.hacimuro.com/images/discord_with_github.png&#34; alt=&#34;1711653907140&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So from a personal level we need to address if this a technical or a business problem. Never the less we cant solve this fancy problems at a hackathon so instead my team started manually asking people for this information. This is when we realised that most members who are part of the hackathon haven&amp;rsquo;t joined the discord/hasn&amp;rsquo;t messaged within the server. This makes our analytics kind of useless since there is little to no value we can equate with no activity. However luckily my team was persistent and we were able to reduce our initial list of 70 github and discord usernames to 25 ish. Another perk of manual data analysis we realised is the cleaning we needed to do. Most people gave us their display names and it there was small information missing from these names too, such as a hidden full stop or Capital letters. Never the less me and my team worked through all of the problems and finally had a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=zvvhJghXfzw&#34;&gt;working demo&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;judging&#34;&gt;Judging&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The juding experience was interesting we were given a room for our track (social/gaming) and we were told to wait. Our team was talking to other teams and we were asked to present. We presented second a friend of mine did a quick explanation tinkering with Farcaster, it wasn&amp;rsquo;t a complete submission. Whilst going up to the stage I accidently palmed the drink of someone. It spilt a little bit and I expressed my sorry, later we found out that this &lt;a href=&#34;https://a16zcrypto.com/team/jay-drain/&#34;&gt;individual&lt;/a&gt; was the judge and representative of a16z crypto 💀. Our presentation went smoothly and answered 2 questions that came from the judge. My opinion on other individuals works were mixed. There was some clearly talented people, a lot of rushed project, some project that felt like the first &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.reddit.com/r/technology/comments/18jyiks/steve_jobs_rigged_the_first_iphone_demo/&#34;&gt;apple demo&lt;/a&gt; and some projects that blurred what they&amp;rsquo;ve built in the hackathon with past work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the end we didn&amp;rsquo;t win the track but I thoroughly enjoyed working with the team and meeting people at the hackathon!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://taikai.network/home-dao/hackathons/ethoxford/projects/cltln8yo7057vw201xzhayuo9/idea&#34;&gt;FINAL SUBMISSION&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;ethglobal-london&#34;&gt;ETHGlobal London&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next week was &lt;a href=&#34;https://ethglobal.com/showcase?events=london2024&#34;&gt;ETHGlobal london&lt;/a&gt; During EthOxford I met some individuals who are very interested in FHE, this is a field that I&amp;rsquo;ve done research and built on before and I truly believe it can revolutionise the world. So for this hackathon I wanted to work on FHEVM which is an EVM application of FHE, I&amp;rsquo;ve heard of companies like Zama and Fhenix building on this and luckily Fhenix had a bounty for this hackathon. So our team of 4 went to the drawing board to start theorising potential applications. Working with a group of new individuals for the first time was intense. Understanding peoples way of working and aligning on a goal was hard to gauge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;ideas&#34;&gt;Ideas&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;FHE changes the mechanism of interacting with systems. Therefore it can be hard to understand where it provides strong utility when building on FHE, taking into consideration the computational overhead drastically restricts its application,  but there are many companies working to &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.techrepublic.com/article/intel-innovation-fully-homomorphic-encryption/&#34;&gt;alleviate this issue&lt;/a&gt;. We came finalised on 4 different ideas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/orgs/zama-ai/projects/27/views/1?pane=issue&amp;amp;itemId=52794552&#34;&gt;FHE DRM&lt;/a&gt;: this is a bounty on zama, so the aim will be to build it on Fhenix then convert the solution to Zama&amp;rsquo;s FHEVM. However after spending some time on it as a team we didn&amp;rsquo;t have a strong idea on how to implement this and wether it is feasible to finish it within the 36 hours.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;FHE Linear Regression: as mentioned previously there are massive computational overhead, however FHE is in a great position to implement ML, this was a strong contender and had clear application of using healthcare data in a decentralised and anonymous way, however after speaking to the FHEnix team and assessing the computational feasibility we realised that we&amp;rsquo;d have to wrestle with the Fhenix EVM a lot to able to build and sustain a model. In the future I&amp;rsquo;d was in strong favour to work on this but at the current stage of the EVM it was not feasible due to computational overhead and the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.fhenix.io/cracking-the-code-overcoming-challenges-of-on-chain-fhe-part-1/&#34;&gt;threshold protocol&lt;/a&gt; not being implemented.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;FHE LP: This was a very interesting idea but in my opinion i think we didn&amp;rsquo;t spend enough time to iron out the nuiances of what this will require. The order book is problematic since it&amp;rsquo;s hard to decide what will be encrypted in the LP pool. For example to my understanding if the volume of the LP was encrypted getting quotes will be impossible since the ouput of the rates will be encrpyted. The same issue arrises for price and other elements of a LP.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;FHE Gaming: Most gaming computation is low overhead and there&amp;rsquo;s a strong element of doing computation on private data. There are &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tonk.gg/&#34;&gt;companies&lt;/a&gt; providing this service to the blockchain and On chain gaming has always struggled to find it&amp;rsquo;s footing, on of the reasons being private state. Some basic computation can be comparison checks, this can enable so much within gaming: think wordle,crossword and battle ships.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;battlefheps&#34;&gt;BattleFHEps&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After having a cigarette with a developer from CryptoKitty, we decided that sticking to the game battleships is feasible and more fun. It&amp;rsquo;s a timeless classic. Developing it wasn&amp;rsquo;t to problematic when it came to the smart contracts but there was some tooling on the FHEnix team that didn&amp;rsquo;t work as expected. For example their gas estimation tooling was incorrect, for large computation for encrypted dataset. This was problematic to identify due to the nature of the problem since the transactions were &amp;ldquo;successfully failing&amp;rdquo; it did not help that the testnet and block explorer were also down during some periods of the hackathon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Working with FHE was fun but identify appropiate usecases for FHEVM was more difficult than anticipated, the technology and research needs to mature a lot more to have more robust applications. The judging was fairly swift, we presented our application to the Fhenix Team, got a bunch of merch. In the end we weren&amp;rsquo;t succesful with the bounty. But the individual who did get first place worked on a very interesting project, It was a ZK prover within FHEVM. He&amp;rsquo;s working style really inspired me on how to approach hackathons in the future. He spent, the first 8 hours just writing the pure logic took a nap and spend the remaining time coding it. He definently deserved the prize.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://ethglobal.com/showcase/battlefheps-x90cc&#34;&gt;FINAL SUBMISSION&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;whats-next&#34;&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s next&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I thoroughly enjoy hacking and building small projects, I learn so much and meet amazing people that I will  be at more hackathons soon, there was an interesting opportunity to learn more about FHE at a castle in Germany!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
		<title>EF</title>
		<link>http://www.hacimuro.com/blog/ef/</link>
		<pubDate>Mon, 27 Nov 2023 16:45:59 +0000</pubDate>
		
		<guid>http://www.hacimuro.com/blog/ef/</guid>
		<description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;what-is-ef&#34;&gt;What is EF&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.joinef.com/&#34;&gt;Entrepreneur First EF&lt;/a&gt; (EF),&lt;/em&gt; is a incubator/talent investor program that enables individuals to pursue entrepreneurship with reduced risk. The program is split into 2 3 month sections. Form and IC. During &amp;ldquo;Form&amp;rdquo; you meet other people on the program, who are in the same boat as you, the talent in the room is exceptional and is the feeling is empowering within the office (At least initially). There are people from a wide range of backgrounds and capabilities and I felt that everyone&amp;rsquo;s contributions was worth listening to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Initially within the program I intended on pursuing and building within the FHE space. It was clearly fairly early on that the current paradigms of computation, IE client side encrypting and server side decrypting is a norm that&amp;rsquo;s really hard to change, especially with the costs associated with FHE. When the program started I teamed up with Milette and whilst I believed the teaming was strong we set very strong goals to achieve that in hindsight was unobtainable, we spent to much time ideating within the trustless space. Which is something that ties heavily with FHE and blockchain technologies. We were unable to come up with a strong trustless need that isn&amp;rsquo;t already catered to so we ended the team fairly briefly after 4 days of working together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After doing some desk research in the space I convinced myself that whatever I build within the program must have strong AI appeal. This is due to the LLM craze and funding to the space seemed much easier, since its an easier narrative to sell and it&amp;rsquo;s technically challenging too. For my next paring I was working with Vlad, and we covered a lot of potential ideas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Routing engines for specialised models (GPT marketplace didn&amp;rsquo;t exist at the time). Similar to POE.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We considered providing computation to fine tuning models, and building RAG services.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Output guidance for model generation, IE ensuring the output is JSON compliant&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Security guardrails for LLM, i.e prompt injection prevention and observability tooling for usage and generation of models.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, eventually we ended the pairing due to the constant feeling of getting customer validation for a potential idea, as well as personal differences from work ethic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At this point I felt fairly lost, I made a lot of commitments to security guard rails for LLMs and it was something I found very fascinating. It catered to my skills very well since I have ML and Cyber Security background so I continued going down the rabbit hole, even writing the code for a &lt;a href=&#34;https://arxiv.org/pdf/2310.04451.pdf&#34;&gt;research paper&lt;/a&gt;. But to no avail it was clear to me at this point that if there was not something I do quickly that my time in EF will be over soon. For the remaining time period of EF I went to Turkiye - Istanbul for Dev connect where I fell back in love with blockchain. In the meantime there was attempts at doing co-founding in the last week. However the narrative within the cohort was fairly secluded and most individuals who weren&amp;rsquo;t in a team was shilling ideas and requesting other people to join such ideas. This defeated the whole point of co-founding and I felt all discussions that I had within this realm was de-moralising.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In hindsight I should of focussed on what I enjoyed working, I should of stayed within the blockchain space and initiated my discussions as such, I would of had the same issues but atleast I know I&amp;rsquo;d more more engaged in the realms I enjoy. Also speaking being more open to doing more customer identification and thinking through procedures before reaching out immediately would of been valuable, however this methodology was not favoured by EF where their main mechanism for quantifying success is the number of people who you speak to, which is highly flawed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s next for me? I got a couple jobs in the pipeline, in the meantime I want to travel and I am working on a arbitrage bot , I hope this will keep me engaged for my technical side and I will still be pursuing the startup world, perhaps within an established early stage company or I will be building and release to the wild.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
		<title>Attacking ML Models</title>
		<link>http://www.hacimuro.com/blog/attacking-ml-models/</link>
		<pubDate>Thu, 14 Sep 2023 16:40:39 +0100</pubDate>
		
		<guid>http://www.hacimuro.com/blog/attacking-ml-models/</guid>
		<description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;adversarial-attack&#34;&gt;Adversarial Attack&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;fair-washing&#34;&gt;Fair Washing&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;poisoning-attack&#34;&gt;Poisoning Attack&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;backdoor&#34;&gt;Backdoor&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;membership-inference&#34;&gt;Membership Inference&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;model-extraction-attack&#34;&gt;Model Extraction Attack&lt;/h1&gt;
</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
		<title>Understanding Federated Learning</title>
		<link>http://www.hacimuro.com/blog/understanding-federated-learning/</link>
		<pubDate>Thu, 14 Sep 2023 10:15:57 +0100</pubDate>
		
		<guid>http://www.hacimuro.com/blog/understanding-federated-learning/</guid>
		<description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;what-is-federated-learning-fl&#34;&gt;What is Federated learning (FL)&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;FL aims to train NN via utilising locally trained models and aggregating a global model. This can be done via a variety of networking paradigms most notably centralised and decentralised aggregation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Setup and Initialisation:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Establish a central server (if centralised) and multiple client devices or nodes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Define the machine learning model architecture and hyperparameter.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Data Partitioning:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Each client retains control of its data locally, ensuring data privacy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Clients perform initial preprocessing and data partitioning (e.g. splitting datasets into mini-batches).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Communication Setup:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Establish secure communication channels between clients and the central server (if centralised).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ensure encryption and authentication mechanisms to protect data in transit.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Model Initiation:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The central server initiates by sending an initial model (often pre-trained) to all clients.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;4.5. &lt;strong&gt;Model Initiation - Decentralised&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;local models train on local dataset rather than fine tuning data the initial global model.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;5&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Local Model Training:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Clients perform local model training on their respective datasets using the received model.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Training can include multiple epochs, gradient descent, and other optimisation techniques. (Having consistency across all client models saves headaches and within a decentralised approach it&amp;rsquo;s extremely difficult to aggregate different model architectures.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Model Updates:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;After local training, clients compute model updates (gradients) based on their data.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;These updates are sent securely to the central server or selected peers(decentralised).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Aggregation at the Central Server:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The central server aggregates the received model updates, typically using techniques like Federated Averaging.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It updates the global model with the aggregated gradients.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;7.5. &lt;strong&gt;Aggregation Mechanism - Decentralised training:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Decentralised training requires a consensus mechanism which can aggregate local models in clusters&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use consensus algorithms (e.g. Federated Byzantine Agreement) to agree on a global model.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ensure that all clients eventually converge to a similar model.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;8&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Iterative Process:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Steps 5-7 are repeated iteratively for a predefined number of rounds or until convergence.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The model&amp;rsquo;s performance improves with each round as it learns from diverse data sources.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Model Evaluation and Deployment:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The final global model is evaluated for performance.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Once satisfactory, the model can be deployed for inference tasks.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;sharing-biases&#34;&gt;Sharing biases&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You may of noticed there is no mentioning of sharing biases, this is due to the following reasons:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Data Distribution Variability&lt;/strong&gt;: In FL, clients have different datasets, which can vary significantly in terms of data distribution, characteristics, and biases. Sharing bias terms directly across clients could lead to models that do not work well to all data sources. Local biases allow models to adapt to the idiosyncrasies of each client&amp;rsquo;s data but doesn&amp;rsquo;t convey the same benefits to global models.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Privacy and Security&lt;/strong&gt;: Federated Learning is designed to maintain data privacy and security. Sharing bias terms could potentially reveal sensitive information about a client&amp;rsquo;s data (&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.hacimuro.com/blog/attacking-ml-models/&#34;&gt;Gradient-Based Inference Attack&lt;/a&gt;). By keeping biases local, it ensures that no client can access or infer another client&amp;rsquo;s bias information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Model Flexibility&lt;/strong&gt;: Local biases enable each client to fine-tune the model according to its specific data. This increases the flexibility of the model and its ability to capture client-specific patterns and nuances. Sharing biases would limit this adaptability.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Reduced Communication Overhead&lt;/strong&gt;: Sharing bias terms in addition to model weights would increase the communication overhead in Federated Learning, especially in scenarios with a large number of clients. Minimising the data exchanged between clients and the central server is a key efficiency concern.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
		<title>PET Streaming</title>
		<link>http://www.hacimuro.com/projects/pet-streaming/</link>
		<pubDate>Tue, 15 Aug 2023 10:45:36 +0100</pubDate>
		
		<guid>http://www.hacimuro.com/projects/pet-streaming/</guid>
		<description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-is-pet-streaming&#34;&gt;What is PET-Streaming&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The aim of this project is to provide privacy enchanging technology. Current goals are&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;input&#34;&gt;Input&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Take a stream of cloud data&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;process&#34;&gt;Process&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anonymise the data&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Check if the data within the stream and does appropiate validation - (Does not store) (Catalogue - is verifiied against a list of data assets and data controls)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;output&#34;&gt;Output&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Send the anonymise data to the end user.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;usecase&#34;&gt;Usecase&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The aim is to be able to to take PII data, and provide an api to the dataowner to enable the utilisation of the data by any organisation that they deem fit, without having to worry about the misuse of PII and the end user can ensure the data integrity&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Developments to POC&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Work with json, CSV or anything else&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;create an access control panel&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Audit record of changes - Store locally back to dataowner&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Have a key management system&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Second iteration&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Create file based interface from storage&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Create a different json implementation with stream data&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This will require a message broker&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sync all changes to the audit recorder&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fuzzy search for PII identifiers in the key of the data&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At all stages&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Data Platform End user should have anonymised data&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;psedo anonymised data&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;identifiable data&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;no PII&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
	</item>
	
	<item>
		<title>About</title>
		<link>http://www.hacimuro.com/about/</link>
		<pubDate>Mon, 14 Aug 2023 12:04:39 +0100</pubDate>
		
		<guid>http://www.hacimuro.com/about/</guid>
		<description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;eps10_hellofriendmov&#34;&gt;eps1.0_hellofriend.mov&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;machine-learning-enthusiast-cyber-security-enjoyer-and-professional-automater&#34;&gt;Machine learning enthusiast, Cyber Security enjoyer and professional automater.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you might of guessed from the tittle, I am a fan of Mr Robot. Apart from being an amazing show, with outstanding visuals and audio, the plot is very convoluted. The concept of a small talented group having the ability to bring down an &amp;ldquo;&amp;ldquo;establishment&amp;rdquo; has always appealed to me. I guess it is a bastardised version of the American Dream. Regardless it was mainly because of this show, and other stuff I pursued studying Cyber Security at University, it was within the first month I realised that it isn&amp;rsquo;t as trivial to replicate the plot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Coming to the realisation that taking over a country and ruining it&amp;rsquo;s economy is too much effort. I was introduced to more cyber resilient systems, Peer to Peer networks, Distributed computation and more. This is where I was properly introduced into blockchain technologies. Understanding this system may be a lot more valuable in the future made even more doubtful of viability of Mr Robot V2, regardless it&amp;rsquo;s a good TV show I recommend that you should definitely watch it (you&amp;rsquo;ve already stumbled on this page).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How I got into ML, well my interest in cyber mainly pertains to privacy, and ML is mainly requires a lot of data ,therefore I was interested in Privacy Preserving machine learning solutions PPML. The terabytes of high variance data needs to come from somewhere. So my main interest within the ML space is Federated Learning (FL). Where you get the best of both worlds. The automation, flexibility and general value of ML without intruding on the privacy of the masses you need the data from. This should also encourage more people to actively share their data, since in theory the data should never leave their device. So to learn more I jumped in the deep end, for my University research I made ML models using homomorphic encryption. ML or Homomorphic encryption was not covered within the course at all. Regardless I just wanted to learn about stuff that actually interested me, rather than getting a high grade by doing a generic dissertation on networks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In short, we&amp;rsquo;re losing to much accuracy when training models, creating models and then encrypting it (inference only) is boring because you already did the deed (using a bunch of peoples data). So I was interested in other avenues, like ZK which has specific applications and Secure multi party computing.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
	</item>
	
	</channel>
</rss>